Guide to the Kurt Boone Photographs and Pictorial Works 2012-2019 PR 356
New-York Historical Society
Kurt Boone photographs and pictorial works
2012-2019
New-York Historical Society
Boone, Kurt B.
PR 356
3 Linear feet in one document box and three flat files
The collection includes ten photographic prints by Kurt Boone of subway performers, seven books or booklets of photographs (mostly by Boone) concerning messenger culture and street photography, and seven posters related to Boone's work and bicycling.
Biographical/Historical Note
Kurt Boone was born in Brooklyn, N.Y. in 1959. The New York City-based author, poet, and courier/messenger is known for his work documenting street culture, including graffiti, urban cycling, street performers, subway busking, skateboarding, and spoken word performance.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in two series:
Series I. Photographic Prints
Series II. Other Pictorial Works
Access Restrictions
Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
Series I: The photographs and posters in folder 1 were gifts of Kurt Boone in 2017. The photographs in folder 2 were purchases from the photographer in 2017 (Rosa Teresa) and 2018 (all others in folder 2).
Series II: Purchased from Kurt Boone in 2019.
Scope and Contents Note
The collection includes ten photographic prints by Kurt Boone (born 1959 in Brooklyn) of subway performers, seven books or booklets of photographs (mostly by Boone) concerning messenger culture and street photography, and seven posters related to Boone's work and cycling.
Color photographs.; Posters.; Bicycle messengers.; Street entertainers -- New York (State) -- New York.; Subway stations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Empire State Building (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works.
- Series I. Photographic Prints, 2014-2015, 2017; 1.5 Linear feet in two flat files
  Scope and Contents
  This collection consists of ten 16x20" color photographs of subway performers taken by Kurt Boone mostly in 2015 (one was taken in 2014) as part of his "Subway Beats" project. In addition, there are two posters advertising a related 2017 exhibition of Boone's photographs, Music in the Tunnels, held at Quimby's Bookstore in Williamsburg, Brooklyn.
  The specific photographs in the collection are itemized in the container list below. Titles, dates and locations used in this finding aid are not found on the photographs themselves, but were provided by Kurt Boone in the collection's transactional documents
  Arrangement
  The photographs are arranged in the container list alphabetically by title, with posters at the end of the list. Purchased photographs are in a separate folder from donated photographs.
  - Accordion Player, 2015 (Box Flat File, Folder 2)
    Location: 42nd Street/6th Avenue
  - Alice Tan Ridley, 2015 (Box Flat File, Folder 2)
    Location: 42nd Street/Times Square
  - Ebony Hillbillies, 2015 (Box Flat File, Folder 2)
    Location: Times Square/42nd Street
  - Jeff Masing (One Man Band), 2015 April 19 (Box Flat File, Folder 1)
    Location: MTA Music Union Square/14th Street Station Stage
  - Larry Wright & Sonia Wright, 2015 (Box Flat File, Folder 2)
    Location: Union Square
  - Maxidekalu, 2014 June 9 (Box Flat File, Folder 1)
    Location: MTA Music Times Square/42nd Street Station Stage
  - Mike Groisman, 2015 March 30 (Box Flat File, Folder 1)
  - Rosa Teresa, 2015 May 20 (Box Flat File, Folder 2)
    Location: 23rd Street and 6th Avenue Station.
  - The Silver Cowboy (Three Dancers in Paint), 2015 February 24 (Box Flat File, Folder 1)
    Location: Times Square/42nd Street Station
  - Trumpet Player (Artist Name Unknown), 2015 April 11 (Box Flat File, Folder 1)
    Location: 59th Street and Lexington Avenue Station
  - Poster for the Music in the Tunnels photo exhibition at Quimby's Bookstore in Brooklyn., 2017 (Box Flat File, Folder 1)
    Poster features a photo of the Saw Lady, subway performer.
  - Poster for the Music in the Tunnels photo exhibition at Quimby's Bookstore in Brooklyn, 2017 (Box Flat File, Folder 1)
    Poster features a photo of Rosa Teresa, subway performer.
- Series II. Other Pictorial Works, 2012-2019; 1.5 Linear feet in one document box and one flat file
  The series is organized by genre/format.
  The series primarily includes books or booklets of photographs, most of which are connected with Kurt Boone as photographer or as author of text. The books generally concern street photography, messenger culture, and cycling. There are a few posters, two of which relate to the books, and others relate to film and a film festival centered on cycling. All items are listed in the container list.
  - Book: "NYC Street Portraiture", 2019 (Offsite-box 1)
    Photography by Kurt Boone. Autographed by Boone.
  - Book: "The Culture of Messenger Bags", 2019 (Offsite-box 1)
    Photography by Kurt Boone (with other credits). Autographed by Boone.
  - Book: "Urgent Document: Messenger Culture: Exhibition Catalog" (see poster below), 2018 (Offsite-box 1)
    Photography by Kurt Boone & JC Ramirez. Autographed by Boone.
  - Book: "Messenger 841 Pro Pouch Book", undated (Offsite-box 1)
    Photography by Kurt Boone (and other credits). Autographed by Boone. Includes "mess life poems" by Boone.
  - Book: "Eye Level: Empire State Building", undated (Offsite-box 1)
    Photography by Michaelle Chapoteau. Text by Kurt Boone. Autographed by both.
  - Book: "Brooklyn Cruise Terminal: Red Hook Criterium Portraits", 2018 (Offsite-box 1)
    Portrait photographs of cyclists taken by Harry Zernike in a pop-up studio at the Red Hook Crit Brooklyn in 2018.
  - Periodical: "G-Shock: Profiles", 2014 (Offsite-box 1)
    Vol. 3: Skate. Related to skateboarding.
  - Poster: "Urgent Document: Messenger Culture: A Photo Exhibition" (see book above), 2018 (Box Flat File, Folder 3)
  - Poster: "Eye Level: Empire State Building" (see book above), undated (Box Flat File, Folder 3)
    Autographed by both Boone and photographer Chapoteau.
  - Poster for movie "Premium Rush", 2012 (Box Flat File, Folder 3)
  - Poster for movie "Line of Sight" at Bicycle Film Festival, 2012 (Box Flat File, Folder 3)
  - Poster for panel discussion "The Urban Playground", 2012 (Box Flat File, Folder 3)
    Event at Eastern Mountain Sports store in Soho; panel discussion moderated by Kurt Boone. Poster autographed by Boone. Poster design by Brice Losinski. Art by Greg Ugalde.
  - Poster: "18th Annual Bicycle Film Festival, New York", 2018 (Box Flat File, Folder 3)